<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://qatcanstem.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://qatcanstem.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-08-05T15:01:59-03:00</updated><id>https://qatcanstem.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Queer Atlantic Canadian STEM</title><subtitle>Improving Diversity, Equity, and Inclusion for Queer Folks in STEM across the Atlantic Provinces (and beyond!)</subtitle><author><name>Your Name</name></author><entry><title type="html">Atlantic Canadian STEMist - Tam Pham</title><link href="https://qatcanstem.github.io/TamPham/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Atlantic Canadian STEMist - Tam Pham" /><published>2020-06-22T00:00:00-03:00</published><updated>2020-06-22T00:00:00-03:00</updated><id>https://qatcanstem.github.io/TamPham</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://qatcanstem.github.io/TamPham/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Profiles/TP.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image-center&quot; class=&quot;align-center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;name-tam-pham&quot;&gt;Name: Tam Pham&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;pronouns-shehethey&quot;&gt;Pronouns: She/He/They&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-do-you-identify-pansexual-genderfluid-person-of-colour&quot;&gt;How do you Identify: Pansexual Genderfluid Person of Colour&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;website-linkedin&quot;&gt;Website: &lt;a href=&quot;linkedin.com/in/tampham2&quot;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;twitter-tampham98392156&quot;&gt;Twitter: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/TamPham98392156&quot;&gt;@TamPham98392156&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;current-job-msc-student-at-the-rainey-lab&quot;&gt;Current Job: M.Sc student at the Rainey Lab&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;scientific-fielddiscipline-structural-biology-biophysics-gpcr-protein-interaction&quot;&gt;Scientific Field/Discipline: Structural biology, Biophysics, GPCR protein interaction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;affiliation-department-of-biochemistry-and-molecular-biology-of-dalhousie-university&quot;&gt;Affiliation: Department of Biochemistry and Molecular Biology of Dalhousie University&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;tell-us-about-yourself&quot;&gt;Tell Us about yourself:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a M.Sc student at the Rainey lab from Department of Biochemistry and Molecular Biology, Dalhousie University. My research interest is centered around understanding protein structure-function correlation using a biophysical technique called Nuclear Magnetic Resonance (NMR). Because of my unique identity as an immigrant QTBIPOC individual, I come to realize the lack of representations in the Atlantic Canada academic settings, STEM field and throughout my life. I encountered QTBIPOC folks who felt that they were “left out” from the conversation when it comes to 2SLGBTQ+ issues whether personal or professional environment. It motivates me to become more involved with 2SLGBTQ+ advocacy whether in my personal free time with the Nova Scotia Rainbow Action Project (NSRAP) or in the STEM field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tell-us-about-your-work&quot;&gt;Tell us about your work:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I study about the apelinergic system in humans. This system has many therapeutic targets for the treatment of cardiovascular diseases, diabetes, obesity and cancer. The system comprises of the apelin receptor, apelin and apela isoforms. My research interest focuses on the interaction between two known apelin isoforms (apelin-55 and apelin-36) with the apelin receptor using a variety of NMR techniques.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;who-are-your-lgbtq-role-models&quot;&gt;Who are your LGBTQ+ role models?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;George Takei has always been one of the few BIPOC LGBTQ+ celebrities who uses his platform to promote spreading love and acceptance towards and within the 2SLGBTQ+ communities. I stand for his motto and strive to be like him one day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;where-do-you-see-yourself-in-5---10-years&quot;&gt;Where do you see yourself in 5 - 10 years?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 5 – 10 years from now, I envision myself as someone who can actively do research and mentor the upcoming generation of scientists. As someone working towards more inclusivity and acceptance for communities, I would still continue to advocate and be the voice for the visible minorities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-would-you-like-to-change-about-academia-or-equivalent-to-make-it-more-welcoming-to-lgbtq-folks&quot;&gt;What would you like to change about Academia (or equivalent) to make it more welcoming to LGBTQ+ folks?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing that I would like to change about the current educational system is reducing the promotions of hate speech such as xenophobia, homophobia, transphobia, biphobia, etc… I encountered occasions where people with high positions in the academia utilizing their position to spread their hatred to others. In my humble opinions, as someone who happens to exist in the intersectionality of multiple marginalized identities, I do not want the existence of hate speech to discourage folks from their aspirations and dreams.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Your Name</name></author><summary type="html">As someone who happens to exist in the intersectionality of multiple marginalized identities, I do not want the existence of hate speech to discourage folks from their aspirations and dreams.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Queer Atlantic Canadian STEMist - Rachel Clarke</title><link href="https://qatcanstem.github.io/RachelClarke/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Queer Atlantic Canadian STEMist - Rachel Clarke" /><published>2019-09-05T00:00:00-03:00</published><updated>2019-09-05T00:00:00-03:00</updated><id>https://qatcanstem.github.io/RachelClarke</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://qatcanstem.github.io/RachelClarke/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Profiles/RC.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image-center&quot; class=&quot;align-center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;name-rachel-clarke&quot;&gt;Name: Rachel Clarke&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-do-you-identify-queer-and-bisexual&quot;&gt;How do you Identify: Queer and bisexual&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;twitter-rachelgclarke&quot;&gt;Twitter: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/RachelGClarke&quot;&gt;@RachelGClarke&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;current-job-msc-candidate&quot;&gt;Current Job: MSc. candidate&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;scientific-fielddiscipline-mercury-photochemistry&quot;&gt;Scientific Field/Discipline: Mercury photochemistry&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;affiliation-acadia-university&quot;&gt;Affiliation: Acadia University&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;tell-us-about-yourself&quot;&gt;Tell Us about yourself:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I study at Acadia University, I’m also queer and bisexual. I am an eclectic environmentalist, a novice knitter, a devoted cat-Mom, and an avid podcast listener. Aside from my research, I am interested in science communication and LGBTQ+, mental health stigma, and feminist issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;tell-us-about-your-work&quot;&gt;Tell us about your work&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mercury, a neurotoxic and endocrine-disrupting chemical, can be removed naturally from water through a chemical reaction called photoreduction, which is facilitated by ultraviolet (UV) radiation. My research project aims to get a better idea of how salinity and dissolved organic matter concentration influence these chemical reactions in estuaries. Understanding these factors can help us better predict mercury retention in these environments. My research is supported by the Arthur Irving Graduate Scholarship in Environmental Studies and an NSERC Canada Graduate Scholarship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-is-your-work-informed-by-your-identity-as-an-lgbtq-person&quot;&gt;How is your work informed by your identity as an LGBTQ+ person?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My identity as an aspiring scientist and my sexual identity are two very large parts of who I am. As someone who identifies as bisexual, being comfortable and secure in myself has been very important to me. I am more passionate about and am more fulfilled by my work when I am comfortable and secure in my work environment, and strive to help build and maintain work environments that help people feel the same way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;who-are-your-lgbtq-role-models&quot;&gt;Who are your LGBTQ+ role models?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alan Turing, considered by many to be the father of theoretical computer science, wasn’t given the credit he deserved because he was gay, and ultimately died by suicide at 41 years old. He made a very large contribution to the World War II effort and modern technology, and his loss is an example of the collective loss of potential knowledge from members of the LGBTQ+ community who are discouraged from pursuing science.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;QAtCanSTEM’s own founder Landon Getz has also become a role model of mine. I admire his passion for LGBTQ+ advocacy and community building, and I’m very excited to see what QAtCanSTEM becomes with his leadership!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;where-do-you-see-yourself-in-5---10-years&quot;&gt;Where do you see yourself in 5 - 10 years?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have not yet decided what career route I want to pursue after my Master’s degree. I have been exploring many options that could lead me down many different roads, but the only thing I see clearly 5 - 10 years in the future is being involved in science. 
In short, I hope to still be happy and fulfilled with the work I’m doing in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-would-you-like-to-change-about-academia-or-equivalent-to-make-it-more-welcoming-to-lgbtq-folks&quot;&gt;What would you like to change about Academia (or equivalent) to make it more welcoming to LGBTQ+ folks?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feeling like you have to hide who you are as LGBTQ+ to succeed is incredibly disheartening and stifling. Having to be two different people on a daily basis is exhausting, and in general I think our work environments should strive to foster acceptance and diversity. Everyone should be able to be who they are without fear!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;any-other-comments&quot;&gt;Any other comments?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you can attend QAtCanSTEM, I look forward to meeting you soon!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Your Name</name></author><summary type="html">I am more passionate about and am more fulfilled by my work when I am comfortable and secure in my work environment, and strive to help build and maintain work environments that help people feel the same way.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Queer Atlantic Canadian STEMist - Landon J. Getz</title><link href="https://qatcanstem.github.io/LandonGetz/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Queer Atlantic Canadian STEMist - Landon J. Getz" /><published>2019-08-21T00:00:00-03:00</published><updated>2019-08-21T00:00:00-03:00</updated><id>https://qatcanstem.github.io/LandonGetz</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://qatcanstem.github.io/LandonGetz/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Profiles/LG.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image-center&quot; class=&quot;align-center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;name-landon-getz&quot;&gt;Name: Landon Getz&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-do-you-identify-queer-and-gay&quot;&gt;How do you Identify: Queer and Gay&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;website-httpwwwlandongetzcom&quot;&gt;Website: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.landongetz.com&quot;&gt;http://www.landongetz.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;twitter-landongetz&quot;&gt;Twitter: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/landongetz&quot;&gt;@landongetz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;current-job-phd-candidate&quot;&gt;Current Job: PhD Candidate&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;scientific-fielddiscipline-microbiology-bacteriology-specifically&quot;&gt;Scientific Field/Discipline: Microbiology (Bacteriology specifically)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;affiliation-dalhousie-university&quot;&gt;Affiliation: Dalhousie University&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;tell-us-about-yourself&quot;&gt;Tell Us about yourself:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a Queer and Gay PhD Student studying at Dalhousie University. I am an LGBTQ+ Advocate and an amateur home bread baker. I am interested in ethics in science and the relationship between science and society. I am an enthusiastic Cat-Dad to a target tabby named Susan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;tell-us-about-your-work&quot;&gt;Tell us about your work&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am studying an ocean an ocean bacteria called &lt;em&gt;Vibrio parahaemolyticus&lt;/em&gt; (and bacteria related to it) to get a better idea of how they metabolize carbon in the environment. These organisms grow better at warmer temperatures and lower salinity, so as the ocean warms through climate change, we can expect to see more Vibrio around. We are primarily concerned with what that might mean, and are doing important research to identify how they might respond to climate change. My work is support by a Killam Predoctoral Scholarship and a Vanier Canadian Graduate Scholarship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-is-your-work-informed-by-your-identity-as-an-lgbtq-person&quot;&gt;How is your work informed by your identity as an LGBTQ+ person?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My identity as a gay man is an integral part of who I am, and therefore informs pretty much everything I do. Most importantly, being comfortable with my own identity has allowed me to ensure that the spaces that I create (be that a laboratory, classroom, community, etc) is a space that is open and welcoming to all. I have made it my mission to ensure that LGBTQ+ folks are always welcome in the spaces that I occupy.
As the founder of QAtCanSTEM, I am trying to build a community for LGBTQ+ STEM folks in Atlantic Canada to find role models and a community. I wanted my profile to be first so that I can make the first step and hold out my hand for others to follow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;who-are-your-lgbtq-role-models&quot;&gt;Who are your LGBTQ+ role models?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr. Alex Bond, the senior curator in charge of birds at the Natural History Museum, encouraged me to attend (and hosted me) the LGBTSTEMinar in 2019 in London, UK. Attending this event gave me the motivation to launch QAtCanSTEM and the QAtCanSTEM Colloquium, and I can’t thank him enough for everything he’s done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;where-do-you-see-yourself-in-5---10-years&quot;&gt;Where do you see yourself in 5 - 10 years?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My immediate goal is to stay in academia and some day (maybe in 10 years?) have my own lab. I am well-aware of the availability of academic jobs however, and have kept doors open in biotechnology and ethics in science. I don’t know what i’ll be doing in 10 years, but i’m excited to find out!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-would-you-like-to-change-about-academia-or-equivalent-to-make-it-more-welcoming-to-lgbtq-folks&quot;&gt;What would you like to change about Academia (or equivalent) to make it more welcoming to LGBTQ+ folks?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I could change something about our environments to make it more welcoming to LGBTQ+ folks, I would make it so everyone knows why it’s so important for me to be able to be gay in the workplace. For me it’s about being able to be myself (and be comfortable with it) in every environment I find myself in. For me, it’s about being able to express myself so I can do my best work. It’s for this reason that I will keep working for the inclusion of everyone in STEM, including LGBTQ+ folks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;any-other-comments&quot;&gt;Any other comments?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I encourage any other Atlantic Canadians, or former Atlantic Canadians, to fill out the profile submission form and join our ranks. I’m excited to meet all your smiling faces!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Your Name</name></author><summary type="html">As the founder of QAtCanSTEM, I am trying to build a community for LGBTQ+ STEM folks in Atlantic Canada.</summary></entry></feed>